{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Through the Looking-Glass","incorrectAnswers":["Mio, My Son","Jonathan Strange & Mr Norrell","The Stand"],"question":"In which of these books does 'Alice in Wonderland' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ivan Turgenev","incorrectAnswers":["Leo Tolstoy","Henryk Sienkiewicz","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Mumu'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Tommyknockers'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Doodle Sack","incorrectAnswers":["Fipple","Tittynope","Quire"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'Old English word for bagpipe'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Chronicles of Narnia","incorrectAnswers":["Harry Potter","The Neverending Story","Divergent"],"question":"In which book series does 'Lucy Pevensie' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which band had Freddie Mercury as its lead vocalist?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Francis Bacon","incorrectAnswers":["Johann Sebastian Bach","Shih Huang Ti","Charles Darwin"],"question":"Which influential historical person created the scientific method and was a key figure in the scientific revolution of the enlightenment?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"handwriting for the purpose of analysing the character of the writer","incorrectAnswers":["venereal diseases","race","intonation in speech"],"question":"What is Graphology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Robins","incorrectAnswers":["The Red Devils","The Whites","The Hatters"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Bristol City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Martin Scorsese","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Alfred Hitchcock"],"question":"Which director directed The Departed?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"3","incorrectAnswers":["1","5","7"],"question":"What is the maximum amount of points that can be scored from a single shot in basketball?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Pink Panther","incorrectAnswers":["Apocalypse Now","The Treasure of the Sierra Madre","Fargo"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Inspector Jacques Clouseau'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Martin Scorsese","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Alfred Hitchcock"],"question":"Which director directed Gangs of New York?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Capybara","incorrectAnswers":["North American Beaver","Eurasian Beaver","Muskrat"],"question":"What is the world's largest rodent? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yaren District","incorrectAnswers":["Dili","Manila","Libreville"],"question":"What is the capital city of Nauru?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Burt Lancaster","incorrectAnswers":["James Stewart","John Wayne","Bill Murray"],"question":"Which actor played the role of J. J. Hunsecker in Sweet Smell of Success?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Central America","incorrectAnswers":["China","Central Asia","Europe"],"question":"Where in the world are bell peppers originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"N'Djamena","incorrectAnswers":["Mogadishu","Ashgabat","Bandar Seri Begawan"],"question":"What is the capital city of Chad?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"A penalty kick","incorrectAnswers":["A free kick","An own goal","A red card"],"question":"What event occurs in soccer when a defender commits a foul in their own penalty area?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Tittynope","incorrectAnswers":["Funambulist","Blatherskite","Winklepicker"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a small quantity of something left over'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Basso","incorrectAnswers":["Alto","Tenor","Baritone"],"question":"Which Italian term for the deepest range of male voice often precedes \"profundo\" or \"profondo\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"13 horizontal stripes of red and white, with a blue rectangle in the top left containing 50 white stars.","incorrectAnswers":["Two equal horizontal bands of blue and yellow.","Red with a white cross that extends to the edges.","Green with a yellow diamond in the center with a blue celestial globe."],"question":"What does the flag of United States look like?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Illinois ","incorrectAnswers":["Texas","Hawaii","Ohio"],"question":"In which US state is Chicago?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Plato","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Paul Sartre","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Friedrich Nietzsche"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'You can discover more about a person in an hour of play than in a year of conversation'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Houston Dynamo","incorrectAnswers":["Houston Saints","Houston Islanders","Houston Fire"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Houston?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["China","Israel","France"],"question":"In which country did the 'Bay of Pigs' invasion take place?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Gordon Lightfoot","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Justin Bieber","Leonard Cohen"],"question":"Which Canadian singer-songwriter and guitarist is known for hit songs such as 'Sundown' and 'The Wreck of the Edmund Fitzgerald'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Argon","incorrectAnswers":["Neon","Helium","Radon"],"question":"What is the name of the inert gas with atomic number 18?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Stanley Baldwin","incorrectAnswers":["Anthony Eden","Winston Churchill","Bonar Law"],"question":"Who Was Prime Minister When King Edward VIII Abdicated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Javanese","incorrectAnswers":["Hausa","Mandarin","Quechua"],"question":"Which of these languages would you find spoken in Indonesia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"John Fogerty","incorrectAnswers":["Paul Andrews","Jimmy Toogood","Bobby Tarbuck"],"question":"Who was the lead singer for Creedence Clearwater Revival?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Javier Bardem","incorrectAnswers":["Jason Bateman","Ken Jeong","Sean Penn"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in films including No Country for Old Men and Skyfall?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Pastern","incorrectAnswers":["Sole","Periople","Hock"],"question":"The part of the foot of a horse between the fetlock and the hoof is the __________","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Argentina","incorrectAnswers":["France","Brazil","England"],"question":"Which country won the 1986 FIFA World Cup, hosted in Mexico?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1917","incorrectAnswers":["1867","1950","1822"],"question":"In which year did the Russian Revolution begin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Afghanistan","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Red Hot Chili Peppers","incorrectAnswers":["The Monkees","Black Flag","Journey"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'Mother's Milk'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Capricorn","incorrectAnswers":["Gemini","Aries","Scorpio"],"question":"If You Were Born On Christmas Day What Star Sign Would You Be?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Baroque","incorrectAnswers":["Classical","Renaissance","Gothic"],"question":"Which 17th and early 18th century movement in painting is characterized by great drama, deep colour, intense light and dark shadows?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Abraham Lincoln","incorrectAnswers":["John F. Kennedy","James Garfield","William McKinley"],"question":"Which American president was assassinated in a theatre?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which American musician sung 'Rock with You'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Casino","incorrectAnswers":["Parasite","Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind","The Godfather"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A mafia enforcer and a casino executive compete against each other over a gambling empire.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Francis Ford Coppola","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Apocalypse Now?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tonga","incorrectAnswers":["Samoa","Mexico","New Zealand"],"question":"Which country altered its timezone in order to be the first to see in the year 2000 ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Little Women","incorrectAnswers":["Buddenbrooks","David Copperfield","Jane Eyre"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line ''Christmas won't be Christmas without any presents''?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"South Africa","incorrectAnswers":["France","United States","Argentina"],"question":"Which country hosted the 2010 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Colorado","incorrectAnswers":["Arizona","Utah","Florida"],"question":"The highest point in Pennsylvania is lower than the lowest point in ______________","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ballistics","incorrectAnswers":["Kinetics","Kinesics","Trajectics"],"question":"Which science deals with the motion of projectiles? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Guyana","incorrectAnswers":["United States of America","Cuba","New Zealand"],"question":"Georgetown is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","China","Indonesia"],"question":"In what country did \"Sepoy Mutiny\" occur? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Where The Crawdads Sing","incorrectAnswers":["Snakehead Swamp","Landlines","Ulysses"],"question":"Which novel by Delia Owens begins with the opening: ‘Marsh is not swamp. Marsh is a space of light’","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Made it, Ma! Top of the world!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Toga! Toga!\"","\"A boy's best friend is his mother.\"","\"Hasta la vista, baby.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'White Heat'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Villans","incorrectAnswers":["The Seagulls","The Hornets","The Seasiders"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Aston Villa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yellow","incorrectAnswers":["Maroon","Blue","White"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Ghana?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mozzarella ","incorrectAnswers":["Gorgonzola","Parmezan","Gouda"],"question":"What Type Of Cheese Is Traditionally Made From Buffaloes Milk?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kigali","incorrectAnswers":["Kuala Lumpur","Bishkek","Ljubljana"],"question":"What is the capital city of Rwanda?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Saudi Arabia","incorrectAnswers":["Qatar","Bahrain","Iran"],"question":"Which of these countries borders United Arab Emirates?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Age Sex Location","incorrectAnswers":["Anybody Seen Lately?","Awesome Situation Logged","Any Souls Loggedin?"],"question":"If someone typed the letters 'ASL' in a message, what would they mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Edgar Allan Poe","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Mario Puzo"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Bells'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George II","incorrectAnswers":["William I","James III","Richard II"],"question":"Who Was The Last British Monarch Born Abroad?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Robert Smith","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Lawrence","John Martin","Jack Austin"],"question":"Who was the lead singer of the Cure?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Portugal","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","The Philippines","Greece"],"question":"What country are the Azores islands a part of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Javier Bardem","incorrectAnswers":["Jason Bateman","Ken Jeong","Sean Penn"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Skyfall and The Sea Inside?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Paraguay","incorrectAnswers":["France","Tonga","Montenegro"],"question":"Asunción is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Apia","incorrectAnswers":["Lomé","Maputo","Podgorica"],"question":"What is the capital city of Samoa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Jamaica","incorrectAnswers":["Tuvalu","Singapore","Micronesia"],"question":"Kingston is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Stephen Hawking","incorrectAnswers":["Albert Einstein","Richard Feynman","Charles Darwin"],"question":"Who wrote 'A Brief History of Time'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Javelin","incorrectAnswers":["Shot put","Discus","Hammer throw"],"question":"Which Olympic sport involves throwing a spear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Leeches","incorrectAnswers":["Vampire Bats","Cobras","Wasps"],"question":"What Creatures Were Frequently Used To Bleed Patients In The Nineteeth Century?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Trees","incorrectAnswers":["Agriculture","Crayfish","Ionising radiation"],"question":"What is Dendrology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Bhutan is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A veteran sets out to reform his neighbor who tried to steal his prized possession.","incorrectAnswers":["A surgeon rescues a disfigured man who is mistreated while scraping a living as a side-show freak.","A young boy, left without attention, delves into a life of petty crime.","A young girl and her dog are swept away by a tornado from their Kansas farm to a magical land."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Gran Torino?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A mummy","incorrectAnswers":["A zombie","A skeleton","A vampire"],"question":"What is the name of the bandaged walking dead often seen during Halloween, whose name comes from the Persian word for 'wax'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Andre Agassi","incorrectAnswers":["Roger Federer","Pete Sampras","Andy Roddick"],"question":"In April 2003 Who Became The Oldest Man To Be Rated No1 In The World Tennis Association Rankings At The Age Of 33?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The wind-up","incorrectAnswers":["The pitch","The strike","The charge"],"question":"Which of these is a legal pitching position in baseball?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Metallica","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Cooper","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the studio album 'Ride the Lightning'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jackie Chan","incorrectAnswers":["Jet Li","Bruce Lee","Donnie Yen"],"question":"Which Chinese action star has broken a number of bones doing stunts and acted in films like 'Drunken Master' and 'Rumble in the Bronx'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"General Custer","incorrectAnswers":["General Lee","General Grant","General Nelson"],"question":"Who was defeated at the Battle of Little Bighorn?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South Sudan","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","Turkmenistan","Laos"],"question":"Juba is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bangkok","incorrectAnswers":["Tokyo","Shanghai","Beijing"],"question":"Which Asian city is home to the Wat Traimit temple, which houses a 5 1/2-ton solid gold Buddha statue?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Iron Maiden","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Squeeze"],"question":"Which English heavy metal band released the song 'Aces High'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Wonton","incorrectAnswers":["Sushi","Sashimi","Tempura"],"question":"Which of these is not a Japanese dish?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Motor Racing","Ice Hockey","Cricket"],"question":"With which sport is Grete Waitz associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Canada","incorrectAnswers":["Belize","Guatemala","Cuba"],"question":"Which of these countries borders United States of America?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Priest-chokers","incorrectAnswers":["Little ears","Fine hair","Rings"],"question":"The pasta strozzapreti has what meaning in Italian?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"fungi","incorrectAnswers":["male health and disease","plankton","music"],"question":"What is Mycology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Blue Whale","incorrectAnswers":["African Elephant","Hippopotamus","Sperm Whale"],"question":"What Is The Worlds Largest Mammal?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"London","incorrectAnswers":["Dublin","Brussels","Ghent"],"question":"Where is Euston Station?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which band includes 'George Harrison'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Amor vincit omnia","incorrectAnswers":["Fortiter et fideliter","Memento vivere","Sic infit"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases means 'Love conquers all'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Henderson the Rain King","incorrectAnswers":["The Moviegoer","The Old Man and the Sea","Howards End"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Eugene Henderson'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Dire Straits","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","The Moody Blues","The Shadows"],"question":"Which band includes 'Mark Knopfler'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Russia","Spain"],"question":"Germany's WWI allies were Austria-Hungary, Bulgaria, and ________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Who released the album 'Lemonade'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Suez Canal","incorrectAnswers":["The Panama Canal","The Kiel Canal","The Grand Canal"],"question":"What man-made waterway did the 1979 Israel-Egypt Peace Treaty allow Israel access to?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Adidas","incorrectAnswers":["Reebok","Puma","Nike"],"question":"Which Sportswear Company Is The Brand With The Three Stripes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Washington ","incorrectAnswers":["Seattle","New York","Atlanta"],"question":"In what city is The Smithsonian Institute? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A swarm","incorrectAnswers":["A stud","A labour","A muster"],"question":"What is the word for a group of gnats?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Adolf Hitler","incorrectAnswers":["Josef Stalin","Karl Marx","Vlademir Lenin"],"question":"Who wrote \"Mein Kampf\" (My Struggle)?","difficulty":"medium"},